export const SOCIALSTUDIESA2010 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. Laws that are made by civilian governments are usually referred to as",
A: "customs.",
B: "acts.",
C: "decrees.",
D: "precedents",
answer: "B. acts",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. An accepted customary practice which has evolved over time is referred to as a",
A: "convention.",
B: "constitution.",
C: "bye-law.",
D: "regulations.",
answer: "A. convention",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. Entrenching fundamental human rights in the constitution of a state ensures the",
A: "effective control of institutions",
B: "Protection of the individual.",
C: "independence of the judiciary.",
D: "Economic well-being of citizens.",
answer: "B. Protection of the individual",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. Democratic style of leadership results in",
A: "prosperity.",
B: "friendliness.",
C: "creativity.",
D: "self-centredness.",
answer: "C. creativity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. Which of the following sectors of the Ghanaian economy employs the largest number of people?",
A: "Mining.",
B: "Manufacturing",
C: "Tourism.",
D: "Agriculture.",
answer: "D. Agriculture",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. An essential feature of democratic governance is",
A: "rule by decree.",
B: "press censorship.",
C: "periodic elections.",
D: "selection of candidates.",
answer: "C. periodic elections",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. A marriage where the couple lives with the wife’s family is",
A: "duolocal.",
B: "matrilocal.",
C: "neolocal.",
D: "patrilocal.",
answer: "B. matrilocal",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. A person who fails to appreciate himself is said to have a poor",
A: "self-image.",
B: "imagination.",
C: "socialization.",
D: "educational background.",
answer: "A. self-image",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. Which of the following can guide a person to behave properly in a society?",
A: "Acquisition of wealth.",
B: "Having many children.",
C: "Provision of basic necessities of life.",
D: "Obeying rules and regulations.",
answer: "D. Obeying rules and regulations",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. The term culture means the",
A: "dress code of a people.",
B: "way of life of a people.",
C: "social control systems.",
D: "way people worship their ancestors",
answer: "B. way of life of a people",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. Which of the following is part of the social environment?",
A: "religion.",
B: "climate.",
C: "money.",
D: "roads.",
answer: "A. religion",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. The individual can help in promoting community development in the following ways except",
A: "paying development levies.",
B: "contributing resources for projects.",
C: "participating in development projects.",
D: "practising a religion.",
answer: "D. practising a religion",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. Labour is said to be skilled when it",
A: "acquires more hands for work.",
B: "performs its work with longer hours.",
C: "has gone through training.",
D: "uses more physical than mental ability.",
answer: "C. has gone through training",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. A purchase day book is a book in which",
A: "all the goods sold are recorded.",
B: "all the cash purchases are recorded.",
C: "records of debtors are kept.",
D: "records of all goods purchased on credit are kept.",
answer: "D. records of all goods purchased on credit are kept",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. In business the term plough back means to",
A: "re-invest profit.",
B: "restore profit.",
C: "redistribute profit.",
D: "float shares.",
answer: "A. re-invest profit",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. Which of the following will help preserve our forests?",
A: "Encouraging small scale mining.",
B: "Keeping sacred groves.",
C: "Planting cover crops.",
D: "Observing fire festivals.",
answer: "B. Keeping sacred groves",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. The most important factor to be considered in community development is",
A: "availability of natural resources.",
B: "prioritization of problems.",
C: "public education.",
D: "visionary leadership.",
answer: "D. visionary leadership",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. An overdraft is a facility which allows an individual to",
A: "keep money in the bank for a long time.",
B: "take an amount more than what is in his account.",
C: "make payment by cheque.",
D: "open more than one account.",
answer: "B. take an amount more than what is in his account",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. The benefit Ghana derives from sustained growth and development is",
A: "saving of funds for sustained development.",
B: "continued membership in international organization.",
C: "improvement in multiparty democracy.",
D: "decrease in ethnic tension.",
answer: "A. saving of funds for sustained development",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. The individual can contribute to national development by",
A: "joining a political party.",
B: "attaining higher education.",
C: "acquiring wealth.",
D: "paying taxes.",
answer: "D. paying taxes",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. One problem associated with political independence in Ghana is",
A: "misapplication of resources.",
B: "religious intolerance.",
C: "high rate of illiteracy.",
D: "increase in population.",
answer: "A. misapplication of resources",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. The best way to control drug abuse among the youth in Ghana is through",
A: "long term imprisonment of offenders.",
B: "education and counselling.",
C: "the formation of youth clubs.",
D: "the establishment of apprenticeship centres.",
answer: "B. education and counselling",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. The best way Ghana can help reduce poverty is",
A: "embarking family planning campaign.",
B: "limiting ministerial appointments.",
C: "controlling prices of goods and services.",
D: "securing foreign loans.",
answer: "A. embarking family planning campaign",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. One of the consequences of deviant behaviour in society is",
A: "increase in rural-urban migration.",
B: "unequal development.",
C: "relegation of elders into the background.",
D: "breakdown of law and order.",
answer: "D. breakdown of law and order",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. In Ghana, festivals are celebrated to",
A: "encourage hard work",
B: "earn foreign exchange.",
C: "boost trading activities.",
D: "initiate development projects.",
answer: "D. initiate development projects",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. The best way to improve agriculture productivity in Ghana is to",
A: "employ farmers from abroad.",
B: "adopt appropriate technical training.",
C: "increase the variety of crops.",
D: "increase the acreage of farms.",
answer: "B. adopt appropriate technical training",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. The identification of one’s other self is important because it helps one to know",
A: "what others would like one to be",
B: "who one is born to be.",
C: "who one would like to be.",
D: "how others see one.",
answer: "D. how others see one",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. The body that resolves constitutional disputes in Ghana is the",
A: "Council of State.",
B: "Supreme Court.",
C: "High Court.",
D: "Electoral Commission.",
answer: "B. Supreme Court",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. The most effective way of preventing bushfires is through the",
A: "use of fertilizers.",
B: "maintenance of ecological balance.",
C: "replanting of trees.",
D: "creation of awareness.",
answer: "D. creation of awareness",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. Culture is said to be dynamic because it",
A: "changes frequently.",
B: "is homogeneous.",
C: "varies from one society to the other.",
D: "must be preserved.",
answer: "C. varies from one society to the other",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. A nation which is rich in natural resources can develop when it has",
A: "sufficient money supply.",
B: "strong political party in power.",
C: "skilled manpower.",
D: "expensive machinery.",
answer: "C. skilled manpower",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. A major problem facing the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) is the",
A: "poor weather conditions in the sub-region.",
B: "absence of a sub-regional high command.",
C: "non-payment of dues by member states.",
D: "absence of a large market.",
answer: "C. non-payment of dues by member states",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. Inter-ethnic marriages help to promote",
A: "hereditary rites.",
B: "conflict resolution.",
C: "national integration.",
D: "formal education.",
answer: "C. national integration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. Population census is beneficial because it",
A: "brings about even development.",
B: "enables the government to provide more job opportunities.",
C: "provides accurate statistics on the number of people.",
D: "helps to make parents more responsible.",
answer: "C. provides accurate statistics on the number of people",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. Which of the following best describes parenting?",
A: "Caring for adopted children.",
B: "Ability to maintain a healthy home.",
C: "Attaining the age of twenty years and above.",
D: "Caring for one’s own children",
answer: "A. Caring for adopted children",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. Productivity measures a worker’s level of",
A: "Education.",
B: "efficiency.",
C: "commitment.",
D: "discipline.",
answer: "B. efficiency",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. The family system which involves both maternal and paternal relatives is described as",
A: "clan.",
B: "extended.",
C: "kinship.",
D: "nuclear.",
answer: "B. extended",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. The population of Ghana is described as youthful because majority of the people",
A: "fall below ten years of age.",
B: "fall below twenty-six years of age.",
C: "are above fourteen years of age.",
D: "are above sixty-five years of age.",
answer: "B. fall below twenty-six years of age",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. In a joint-stock company, risk is borne by the",
A: "brokers.",
B: "employees.",
C: "shareholders.",
D: "board of directors.",
answer: "C. shareholders",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. In matrilineal inheritance, descent is traced along the line of",
A: "father.",
B: "uncle.",
C: "mother.",
D: "sister.",
answer: "C. mother",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. The tendency to consider one’s culture superior to all others is known as",
A: "Nationalism.",
B: "ethnocentrism.",
C: "allegiance.",
D: "patriotism.",
answer: "B. ethnocentrism",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. A gradual reduction in the quality of resources in the environment is referred to as",
A: "deforestation.",
B: "desertification.",
C: "degradation.",
D: "exploitation.",
answer: "C. degradation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. The process of production is said to be complete when the goods",
A: "are priced.",
B: "are packaged.",
C: "reach the warehouse.",
D: "reach the final consumer.",
answer: "D. reach the final consumer",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. Which of the following socio-cultural practices is commonly shared by all the ethnic groups in",
A: "Chieftaincy.",
B: "Puberty rite.",
C: "Betrothal.",
D: "Female circumcision.",
answer: "A. Chieftaincy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. Effective community development is best brought about by",
A: "business managers.",
B: "the individuals.",
C: "country planners.",
D: "religious leaders.",
answer: "B. the individuals",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. An advantage Ghana derives from international co-operation is",
A: "ability to raise large financial capital.",
B: "enjoyment of internal immunity.",
C: "avoidance of taxation on imports.",
D: "preferential treatment of all her citizens.",
answer: "A. ability to raise large financial capital",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. In the traditional Ghanaian society, man’s greatest responsibility is to",
A: "receive visitors and relatives.",
B: "provide the material needs of the family.",
C: "baby-sit when the woman delivers a baby.",
D: "undertake the domestic chores of the family.",
answer: "B. provide the material needs of the family",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. The provisions of the 1992 constitution that cannot be amended easily are referred to as",
A: "bills of rights.",
B: "enshrined clauses.",
C: "entrenched clauses.",
D: "judicial precedence.",
answer: "C. entrenched clauses",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. Which of the following implies that all persons must obey the laws of the land?",
A: "Constitutional rule.",
B: "Constitutional rights.",
C: "Rule of law.",
D: "Fundamental human rights.",
answer: "C. Rule of law",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. The most effective way of increasing production in the public sector of the economy is",
A: "extending working hours.",
B: "intensifying monitoring systems.",
C: "providing more recreational facilities for workers.",
D: "employ more workers.",
answer: "B. intensifying monitoring systems",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question51",
question: "51. The United Nations Organization (UNO) was formed to replace the",
A: "League of Nations.",
B: "Commonwealth of Nations.",
C: "North Atlantic Treaty organization.",
D: "Non-Aligned Movement.",
answer: "A. League of Nations",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question52",
question: "52. The exchange of goods and services among countries is called",
A: "terms of trade.",
B: "balance of trade.",
C: "international trade.",
D: "internal trade.",
answer: "C. international trade",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question53",
question: "53. The principle of self-reliance implies",
A: "using only local raw materials.",
B: "consuming what is produce locally.",
C: "producing what you need.",
D: "producing more than is needed.",
answer: "B. consuming what is produce locally",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question54",
question: "54. What a leader requires from his followers in order to achieve success is to",
A: "dues for his welfare.",
B: "be loyal and co-operative.",
C: "avoid criticizing him.",
D: "sing to praise him.",
answer: "B. be loyal and co-operative",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question55",
question: "55. An important aim of formal education is",
A: "making the individual fit well into the community.",
B: "acquiring vocational skills.",
C: "acquiring higher academic excellence.",
D: "helping the individual well-paid job.",
answer: "A. making the individual fit well into the community",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question56",
question: "56. Which of the following is responsible for the low standard of living in Ghana?",
A: "High mortality rate.",
B: "High dependency ratio.",
C: "Inadequate basic education.",
D: "Inadequate basic infrastructure.",
answer: "B. High dependency ratio",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question57",
question: "57. A resource is classified as renewable when it can be",
A: "exploited with less capital.",
B: "exported for foreign exchange.",
C: "processed into consumer goods.",
D: "replenished before it runs outs.",
answer: "D. replenished before it runs outs",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question58",
question: "58. A major goal of Ghana’s development policy is to",
A: "seek foreign aid.",
B: "raise the standard of living of the people.",
C: "enrich politicians.",
D: "ensure good governance.",
answer: "B. raise the standard of living of the people",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question59",
question: "59. To sustain business organization, the entrepreneur must",
A: "join a trade union.",
B: "employ more of his family members.",
C: "participate regularly in trade fairs.",
D: "separate business accounts from personal accounts.",
answer: "D. separate business accounts from personal accounts",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question60",
question: "60. The capabilities, skills and technical knowledge of a country’s population constitute her",
A: "human resource.",
B: "technical base.",
C: "productive force.",
D: "capital resource.",
answer: "A. human resource",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},



]